<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Garth's Coding Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://garth0323.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://garth0323.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-07T01:17:57+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://garth0323.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Garth Gaughan]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why I am laughing on Nitous.io while I learn RoR]]></title>
    <link href="http://garth0323.github.io/blog/2014/01/06/why-i-am-laughing-on-nitous-dot-io-while-i-learn-ror/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-06T17:48:03+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://garth0323.github.io/blog/2014/01/06/why-i-am-laughing-on-nitous-dot-io-while-i-learn-ror</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am new to Ruby on Rails and coding in general. Up to this point I have
always tried to work in the cloud. I do not like being tied to one machine,
and I hate the idea that I am responsible for saving files and risk losing
them if a machine goes down.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>For example, When Google Music became available I could not wait for an
invite so that I did not have to store alof my music on my phone and
computer. There are drawbacks to working in the cloud but it all comes down
to three major benefits: <strong>Location, Location, Location</strong>.</p>

<p>Using nitrus.io allows me to use any machine, anywhere. Most importantly,
and most impressively I am able to use my Chromebook for RoR development. I
prefer this to my PC, mostly because of battery power. Learning in the Linux
environment that nitrous.io seems like a benefit down the road as well.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trust and Loathing in Ruby]]></title>
    <link href="http://garth0323.github.io/blog/2013/12/31/trust-and-loathing-in-ruby/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-31T22:06:59+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://garth0323.github.io/blog/2013/12/31/trust-and-loathing-in-ruby</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Learning Ruby or probably any language is scary. It is exciting but scary. I
had to learn to trust that things are going to work even when I don&rsquo;t
understand why.</p>

<!-- more -->


<ul>
<li>I understand that A + B = C</li>
<li>But sometimes I don&rsquo;t know how B got it&rsquo;s value so I just test the outcome.</li>
<li>I sometimes Google issues and don&rsquo;t understand the answer, but I test it and it works out.</li>
</ul>


<p>This trust in the community allows me to expirement and stretch beyond what I know now.
I am allowed to mess up knowing that the answer is just a Google search away.
Or maybe 4 hours worth of Google searches away&hellip;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
